Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
David Mendenhall: Hello, friends
Kostadis Roussos: Hello, adventurers
David Mendenhall: Wade, you joining us? Friends
Wade Brown: and Wade.
David Mendenhall: Friends and Wade. Yeah, maybe.
Wade Brown: Maybe. No, that's fair. Looks
David Mendenhall: like you're in a low light situation. Oh, there you go, Wade.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah. No, I'm just... There's Vaseline all over the lens. There we go
Kostadis Roussos: Okay
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let me just see if I can get Gary
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So, uh, Dave?
Wade Brown: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, your, your peculiar take on, um, adventuring gold-
David Mendenhall: Mm.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukradin's rather peculiar approach
Wade Brown: Vukradin.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukradin, right. You have to understand that the entire economy of the area hinges on adventurers.
David Mendenhall: It could prove problematic indeed.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no. No, no. As, as, as, as, as attracted the attention of a group of people.
David Mendenhall: Oh, really? Oh, I like this development. We'll, we'll have to see how that goes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, so, so, so there will be-
David Mendenhall: Other belie- others who believe in organic fair trade gold.
Kostadis Roussos: I, uh... No, I would say others who belie- I wouldn't go that far.
David Mendenhall: You wouldn't go that
Kostadis Roussos: far. It's a big world. I'm sure we could find some species
David Mendenhall: that- We could find some ad- other fellow hippie adventurers who believe in Vukradin's warped sense of morality.
David Mendenhall: Yes. Okay. Well,
Kostadis Roussos: you know, I'm thinking paladins.
David Mendenhall: Maybe. I don't know. I've seen plenty of paladins- I, I- ... who just take the gold.
Kostadis Roussos: You've seen one paladin who just takes the gold.
David Mendenhall: I think I saw one paladin who, like, tried to become evil on purpose for, like, to gain extra power. That was pretty awful and stuck
Kostadis Roussos: I like it. What is the paladin?
David Mendenhall: Uh, it's, uh, Olivier's character.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, he wasn't a paladin then. He was a, uh, he was a rogue.
David Mendenhall: Oh, he was a rogue? Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: No, the paladin was in the, the drow adventure.
David Mendenhall: The paladin was back in the drow adventure? God. Yes. So long ago.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Bayard.
David Mendenhall: Bayard. Oh, okay. Anyway ...
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So I, I have to admit that this weekend I was doing a triathlon.
David Mendenhall: I saw that, yeah. Escape From Alcatraz.
Kostadis Roussos: Escape From Alcatraz. Your
David Mendenhall: second time. Congratulations.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you. Thank you. Um, and as a result, I did not have time to write a summary 'cause I was-
David Mendenhall: Well
David Mendenhall: I
Kostadis Roussos: get-
David Mendenhall: I did not have time to do a triathlon
Kostadis Roussos: So-
David Mendenhall: Gary.
Gary Young: I- one second.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. And then today, I, I have a real job now, unlike my previous, you know, year where I was doing nothing.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And as a result, I didn't even have time to, like ... Anyway, I did not have time this week, so I apologize. Cool. I have to do the boring conventional thing of trying to remember what happened.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Also, does it not generate an AI summary? I think it does
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, it did. It does. Uh So how's everybody's week?
Wade Brown: I'm in hell.
Gary Young: Well- I am India.
David Mendenhall: Well, so hold on. You're back from India. Congratulations, you made it back.
Gary Young: Sorry. Welcome back. No, he's, uh, he's- He was saying, saying something more serious.
Kostadis Roussos: Why were you... Why are you in hell?
Wade Brown: Oh, I... It's not serious. It's just everything I basically left Roku for is, like, in spades here.
Wade Brown: We're now on, like, four or five pre-meetings before I can even get hardware in my hands.
Kostadis Roussos: I- can I just say something? Dave earned that.
Wade Brown: It's, it's-
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Stop, stop, stop ... so God awful. Wait, Dave, Dave, Dave. I
David Mendenhall: never made you go to five pre-meetings.
Kostadis Roussos: D- d- d- Dave, Dave.
David Mendenhall: Never once did I do that.
Kostadis Roussos: You did. You did. Dave did.
Kostadis Roussos: Dave. I did
David Mendenhall: not.
Kostadis Roussos: Other people did. Dave, y- you, you can savor this moment. Savor it
Kostadis Roussos: You are allowed to say- Wade, thank you for sharing.
Wade Brown: I need to come up with every possible eventuality in what is essentially a task of kernel driver debug. Like- This is what happens when you work- I don't know how to plan my next three months around I'm going to look for the bugs in the kernel drivers and I'm going to fix them.
Wade Brown: But they want that, and I won't get hardware until- Yeah,
David Mendenhall: this is where, this is where ChatGPT can help you a lot.
Wade Brown: No, this is where I just quit.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay.
Wade Brown: I'm just a contractor. What are they gonna do, fire me?
David Mendenhall: If you'd be interested in being a virtual machinist at Roku, uh, I had somebody quit today and I have an opening
Wade Brown: A virtual machinist?
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Wade Brown: What is that? I
David Mendenhall: suspect- Would you like to integrate Hermes into the OS?
Wade Brown: Uh, probably not.
David Mendenhall: Well, go look up what it is and then you can think about it.
Wade Brown: Yeah. Hermes?
David Mendenhall: Mm-hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: How about this? You wouldn't have to attend meetings.
Wade Brown: What's the problem? I like doing work, but it's just, it's all meetings. Wall to wall meetings, and it... I can't do shit. And they're like, "Well, we bill hours and do stuff." I'm like, "There's nothing to do."
Kostadis Roussos: So the problem is that you wanna get stuff done, and then there's a whole army of people whose job it is to measure that you're doing stuff.
Wade Brown: I know. Oh, dude, these meetings are insane. It's two engineers and eight managers. Like, it's, it's not an exaggeration. It's me and the FPGA guy and eight PM types. It's fucking nuts. I,
David Mendenhall: I can promise you, you will not have eight PM types. Well,
Kostadis Roussos: so
David Mendenhall: I, it is just- All right. Let's play a game, 'cause I've got... I've had a long day.
David Mendenhall: Let's play a game. Yeah,
Gary Young: sorry. That's all right. Did you not task the project manager with building out the plan for the testing?
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So I, I, I dumped the AI summary so that folks can remember what happened last week. Oh.
David Mendenhall: I remember what happened. We cleared out that previous dungeon and avoided the obvious trap and left it for the dwarves, who are now dead.
Wade Brown: Yeah, I got conked out by an osier jelly, but, uh, our helpful cleric brought me back up.
Gary Young: And then
Wade Brown: for
Gary Young: some unknown reason- I found a bunch of gems ... there was a ma- a, like, a dagger in our inventory. It's great.
David Mendenhall: Vukradin was very unhappy to see that when he looked today.
Wade Brown: Who, Vukradin can get his panties out of a bunch.
Wade Brown: Be more pragmatic.
David Mendenhall: He has definitely not learned pragmatism yet.
Wade Brown: He's too young. Yeah. He's an idealist.
David Mendenhall: I like that. But you know there's always the character arc. We'll see.
Wade Brown: No, I like it. I, I, I... It gives me room to, you know, try to shepherd him out of his, you know, shitheaded teenage days. All
David Mendenhall: right. Maybe you could roll for initiative.
Wade Brown: Are we at a... Oh.
David Mendenhall: We are indeed.
Wade Brown: Yes, we are. Sorry. Uh, I swear I had the, the character sheet open. Where'd it go?
Gary Young: So, uh, Dave, you updated the spreadsheet incorrectly.
David Mendenhall: I'm sorry. Because you need- What did I do?
Gary Young: You, you need the blood money item section, not just the blood money money.
David Mendenhall: That actually did, that actually did occur to me.
David Mendenhall: Feel free to go ahead and do that.
Gary Young: Or, you know, like, an Is Blood Money column.
David Mendenhall: I also considered that. I am, I'm so glad that we are aligned on this objective, Drow.
Gary Young: All right. We're gonna do Is Blood Money.
David Mendenhall: All right. Is Blood Money. Do some of. The Boolean. I,
Kostadis Roussos: I, I have to decide, you know, like, what is for Kro- who does, what is, um, Valphine thinking here?
Kostadis Roussos: What? Well, how, probably
Kostadis Roussos: how come the Drow haven't conquered the Overbrighters and slaughtered them all and made them slaves of the Underdark. Didn't, didn't
David Mendenhall: she say in the la- last week that, um, these are the, the bizarre machinations of surface dwellers?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but, yeah, like, at this point in time, I'm just thinking she's probably thinking that, you know, with, if, th- given how effete you were
Gary Young: Oh.
Gary Young: Just keep in mind that she's not actually evil.
Kostadis Roussos: Fair. But she's a
Wade Brown: drow,
David Mendenhall: and drows are evil. His underscore blood. I love it. A full on variable.
Wade Brown: Can we make like a-
David Mendenhall: So T and F. T, and I guess these... I guess he believes these Gemstones are F. So we'll go with F on that one.
Wade Brown: Can we do like a, a highlighting in Excel, or not Excel, whatever, you know, to put a red tint on anything that's got true in that column?
Gary Young: I'm sure we could write a little bit of a JavaScript.
Gary Young: There, yeah. So we're gonna have to have two summary columns. Uh, it's two sub columns. Uh, I'll, I'll work on it.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, you
Kostadis Roussos: could...
David Mendenhall: Oh, God.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So clearly- I'm having fun ...
David Mendenhall: I just, just, just wanna say something? I, I have to say, I'm having more fun already than I was at the end of Storm Kings. Things are going well.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Well,
Wade Brown: yeah, we're full
Kostadis Roussos: of potential
Wade Brown: right now.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. You know, it was a different era. It, it was... All right. Okay. All right, let me go to the initiative. Work, work, work. Did I roll initiative? Yes. I have numbers. I am sorting
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's the wrong sword
David Mendenhall: Turn it backwards That's upside
Wade Brown: down sword.
Kostadis Roussos: That's right side up All right, Vukradin, you are up first
David Mendenhall: Oh, Jesus. Okay
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, is it... Hold on, hold on,
David Mendenhall: hold on What is going on? Why are these-
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, hold on, hold
David Mendenhall: on We're fighting orcs?
Wade Brown: Vukradin, I thought
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Vukradin. How do I pronounce your name?
Kostadis Roussos: Is it Vukradin, Vukradin, Vukradin?
David Mendenhall: I think Vukradin
Wade Brown: Or V dog. Just call him V dog
Kostadis Roussos: Like, does anyb- Let me ask you a question. Do, does anyone other than your mother and your stalwart fans call you Vukradin? Doesn't anybody use, like, a nickname like Din or Crad or Vuc?
David Mendenhall: I'm a serious musician They use my name.
David Mendenhall: I don't know what you think is going on here.
David Mendenhall: Blue crawdad and we'll be fine, thank
Kostadis Roussos: you. Okay. Do your ca- do your friends call you Kazneporium? Yes. Are they your friends? No. Yes.
David Mendenhall: Exactly. The answer is, what friends? Exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: Are they your friends?
David Mendenhall: KP. No.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Wade Brown: For what it's worth, we can barely see the orcs. We can see maybe, like, two of them. The rest are kind of up here in the fog of war or something.
David Mendenhall: So I'm going first. This is very bad for the party that I'm going first. I would like to parlay with the orcs.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Do you actually walk up to them and say, "I wish to parlay"?
David Mendenhall: Sadly, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Well...
Wade Brown: Oh, that boy is gonna get himself killed.
Gary Young: Pink cushion.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Well, the orcs kind of say,
Kostadis Roussos: uh, the orcs are kind of like, "Cool, he's a dumbass."
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, what they really say is, "He recognizes our rights to this territory, and is offering himself in sacrifice."
David Mendenhall: Sacrifice? No, I just wanted to talk. What is going... Why are you guys here? Like, did you need something? Do you need help? Like, are you looking for a place to stay? Like, are you hungry?
Kostadis Roussos: Well,
Wade Brown: hold on one second. Do you offer to fluff their pillows while you're at it?
David Mendenhall: Very con- I've never encountered orcs before. I'm very confused.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, it's worse than that. You have encountered orcs before, but they were in, um, whatchamacallit? Um... Storm kings. No, no, no. They were, they were in a Neverwinter, and they were civilized.
David Mendenhall: Oh, even better. Very- Now I'm even doubly confused.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: You came and listened to my music.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. I mean, they were- Did you
David Mendenhall: need me to play for you? I don't have my piano with me, but I have a trumpet.
Gary Young: You said a trumpet?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, a trumpet. Okay. You
Gary Young: said trumpet.
David Mendenhall: You said- I also have a clarinet. Would you prefer that?
David Mendenhall: Do, you want the reeded instrument or just the brass?
Wade Brown: So I don't understand any of this, right? He's speaking in Orc, like ...
Kostadis Roussos: Um- Let me see. Uh- Clarinet seems
Gary Young: more appropriate for
Kostadis Roussos: them ... they speak Common and Orc.
David Mendenhall: Um- There you go. Common.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So, um- All right, so he, uh, moves over here. Sorry.
David Mendenhall: And whacks me.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, hold on. Orc number one, sorry. Orc number one kind of is like- What? "Well, so if he's, if you're gonna give us a bonus round, we're gonna take advantage of it." And he reaches with his great ax and effing misses, proving that God loves fools and sinners.
David Mendenhall: All right, you missed. Great. All right, the battle is joined, then.
David Mendenhall: All right, Soma, don't be an idiot like me.
Wade Brown: You got lucky, kiddo.
David Mendenhall: I did.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, let's see. This is where, this is where one of you, um, remembers that there were orc tribes that were coming down from the north.
David Mendenhall: We were told this by, like, the, uh, the mayor of the town or something. The,
Kostadis Roussos: no, the, the innkeeper.
David Mendenhall: The innkeeper, all right.
David Mendenhall: Yep.
Wade Brown: All right, uh, we're gonna go ahead and cast, uh, ice knife on number three.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Let's see. Actually, how high up are they? This is a, this is an incline, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. 20 feet.
Wade Brown: Okay, so theoretically, if I thorn whipped a guy down, would he end up on, like, prone and take damage on the way down?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, yeah, I guess so.
Kostadis Roussos: I think so.
Wade Brown: All right, then maybe that's what we do. We'll just gonna thorn whip number two and drag him down.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, what's the saving throw, or is it a two hit?
Wade Brown: Uh, that's me.
David Mendenhall: 22 hits
Kostadis Roussos: Yep
Wade Brown: It's a hit. Uh- He falls
Kostadis Roussos: down
Wade Brown: Yeah, he d- gets dragged. Let's see. On a hit, the target takes 1d6, and then, uh, pull it 10 feet closer, which means he tumbles down the hill. I assume that knocks him prone or something crazy like that No, it's five
David Mendenhall: feet. You should bring him another five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, it's...
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming this was 20 feet down.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I see. I see. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Okay. Um, so- Take fall damage ... uh, does he take fall damage?
Wade Brown: At the very least, he should be prone or something,
Kostadis Roussos: right? No, no, he's definitely prone. Okay, good. I'm saying, I'm trying to decide if he takes fall damage because he was rolled down.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm. Does he take prone damage? Does he take fall damage? Takes 1D6 worth of fall damage. How about that? That's, I think that's a compromise. That's good
Wade Brown: enough. Uh-
Kostadis Roussos: That works. All right. Doesn't take the full 2D6, that's what I was trying to decide.
Wade Brown: All right, he takes one more.
Kostadis Roussos: So six points of damage?
Wade Brown: Six points on orc number two.
Wade Brown: Yeah. The important thing is he is CC'd. All right. No problem. Uh, init bonus. Uh, somebody already got him. Good. Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. All right, who's next? Orc
David Mendenhall: four.
Kostadis Roussos: Or four. That, is that what I heard?
Wade Brown: I heard arc four.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Arc four. Hmm. All right. I'm currently futzing with technology. That is not a good thing for me to be doing. I should be focused on playing and not on, you know, goofing off with technology, 'cause we all know that technology is in fact the source of all problems in modern society.
Wade Brown: No, it's PMs.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, since we have none here anymore, I suppose we could say that. All right. So you did that. What does number four do? Hmm. Yeah. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So he can, he can move. So he goes one. Goes one, two, three, and is like, "Whatever." Uh, and he will attack, uh, crud in again. Why? Because he's happens to be closest. I mean, he did
Wade Brown: rush up into the front.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he did. So it's, it's not, it's not my fault. Uh, except I forgot to roll to hit
Kostadis Roussos: 18. You take 12 points of damage, Vukradin
David Mendenhall: I am unconscious
Kostadis Roussos: You are unconscious. All right
David Mendenhall: And let me do my death save
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Who's next?
David Mendenhall: I failed
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: I think it's me It's
David Mendenhall: going to be a very painful lesson that I learn
Wade Brown: Well, maybe you won't learn anything. You'll just be dead
David Mendenhall: I'll just be dead.
David Mendenhall: Even better
Gary Young: All right. All right, we'll go with, uh, heal the word, uh, healing word, uh, and then sacred flame
David Mendenhall: All right. You got 11 on a healing word? I didn't even know it could be that powerful. I thought it was like a D4 It's
Gary Young: 2 D4 I, I believe I have some- It says
Wade Brown: 2 D4 plus three in the... He, he
David Mendenhall: double
Wade Brown: crit
David Mendenhall: Wow.
David Mendenhall: Nice. All right, so I have nine hit points. Thank you
Gary Young: And then one point in sacred flame. Up to whom? Uh, we're gonna go with, uh, um... Actually, that's a good question. Uh- Hold on. Prone condition And why is, why is Brewbarry injured? Didn't we do a long rest?
David Mendenhall: We long rested. Yeah, yeah, yeah. We long rested. Yeah, go
Wade Brown: ahead and reset everything.
Gary Young: Well, uh, at any rate, um, uh, it doesn't matter who I'm doing it on, so, uh, it will be on
Gary Young: Four All right
David Mendenhall: Are you raging?
Gary Young: Uh, it is Brewbarry's turn next. Uh- That was foul-feeming. I am... Hmm.
Wade Brown: Did we skip the prone guy?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah. Yeah, I didn't get... Yeah, the prone guy didn't get- He should have gone
Wade Brown: before the cleric.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, well...
Gary Young: Huh? Orc two? Yes. Oh, yeah, you're right, orc two. I
Wade Brown: mean-
Gary Young: Sorry ...
Wade Brown: his only action is stand up, right?
Wade Brown: But
Kostadis Roussos: No, he can, he, prone, the prone condition, you can r- remove the prone condition by reducing your move rate by a 15.
Wade Brown: Oh,
Kostadis Roussos: okay. Right. Uh, Vukradin would still be dead, so move Br- Brewbarry. I'll just do... Can I just do the orc after Brewbarry? How about that? Yeah,
Gary Young: that's
Kostadis Roussos: fine.
David Mendenhall: All
Kostadis Roussos: right, let's go.
David Mendenhall: Just,
Gary Young: it's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Brewbarry, go.
Gary Young: Uh, go smash.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay.
Gary Young: Uh, but he doesn't have to be that close. He can be, like, here, and-
Kostadis Roussos: Yes ...
Gary Young: let's say
Kostadis Roussos: And since he was knocked prone, you do have advantage on him. So roll again. You missed, the 12 missed.
Gary Young: Uh, okay. Um...
Wade Brown: D20 plus 5
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit, seven points of damage
Gary Young: On number two?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep
Gary Young: Which would-
Wade Brown: That'd have been two hit
Gary Young: points
Gary Young: um, kill him.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Fix it.
Gary Young: By the way, did, did, uh, one of the orcs make a saving throw on sacred flame for one hit point?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, number four made a s- oh, I didn't roll that. Number four was the guy... I don't know why he was moved. All right, I'm assuming, uh, what was your sacred flame? Oh, yes, he made his saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: One, one hit point. Made his save. All right.
Gary Young: Okay. Done.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so this orc
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Does this work too? He just got whacked by Brewbarry, so he charges at Brewbarry By the way, what does the cleave action do?
Gary Young: Oh, that's a good question. Cleave, once per turn if I hit a creature with a melee attack, I can make another melee attack against a second creature within one fi- within five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so do your second, so do your second attack.
Gary Young: Okay. Presumably
Kostadis Roussos: a number one. Yep.
Gary Young: That is a hit. Uh, the second creature takes the halberd's damage, but without ability modifier.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: So not this. It would be Uh, that would be a, a nine damage It
Wade Brown: would just be nine, yeah. All right
Gary Young: Nine damage on one
Wade Brown: On one?
Wade Brown: All right.
Gary Young: Hmm. D That's useful. I should, like, actually do that. Yes. All right. So I believe you said that two was, uh, leaving a square that I threaten.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it was advancing to you.
Gary Young: That's correct. He's leaving a square that I threaten.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, fair. Okay, what happens in that case?
Gary Young: That means that I get an attack of opportunity,
David Mendenhall: right?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, fair enough. Fair enough Ah.
Gary Young: Uh- Orc? So that's an 18 to hit. And that's gonna kill him. This dude, if you, if
Wade Brown: you have at least a plus three, you can't not kill him,
Gary Young: so yeah. All right, he dies.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Gary Young: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Well done.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm. All right.
David Mendenhall: Orc one-
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, and I forgot to rage. Hold on. It... All right, what would orc three do?
Kostadis Roussos: Everybody's now decided Vukradin is, is a loser who can't add much value.
Wade Brown: He is a bard.
David Mendenhall: Kill him again.
Gary Young: So did anyone notice that Valphine is yo? I-
Kostadis Roussos: No,
Gary Young: that's because-
Kostadis Roussos: That's what I was
Gary Young: up on No,
David Mendenhall: I, I saw that, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's because it- Oh, that's the texture on the map, isn't
Gary Young: it? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah,
Gary Young: it
Kostadis Roussos: says ca- it's supposed to say canyon. So when your, when your character's over it, it kind of, like, goes in the background so that...
Kostadis Roussos: Anyway.
Wade Brown: It, it's weird that that's on the top layer. Anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: I put it on the top layer. It's, uh, it means that it's no- it, it means that I can put these symbols on where they are and it, they will show regardless of whether you've discovered it or not. Otherwise, if you put it in the other layers and you don't have lighting- Oh
Kostadis Roussos: you can't, you can't see it. So they had this new foreground layer that lets me do that. Um, since this is causing people- How about that? Okay. Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, fine
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just... No, I was- Just curious. No, no, I know, I know. But, you know, it was like it m- I was kind of annoyed by it, and so you guys brought it up and I said, "Okay, it's not g- I'm not gonna look weird be g- by being annoyed."
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay. So, uh, he attacks with his great ax.
Gary Young: On Valphine?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: All right. AC 17
Kostadis Roussos: And it's a hit
Wade Brown: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay.
Wade Brown: One away from a crit at least
Kostadis Roussos: For eight points of damage All right. I'll take it.
Gary Young: All
Kostadis Roussos: right. Down to two. All right. Vukradin.
David Mendenhall: All right. He's understands now that he's fighting for his life here.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he not want to sit there and write a sonnet first?
David Mendenhall: He wants to live.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: He does not have a death wish. He is not-
Wade Brown: He's
David Mendenhall: not
Wade Brown: late stage
David Mendenhall: Orsik ... he's not Orsik.
Kostadis Roussos: Late stage-
David Mendenhall: He does, uh, three damage on number one, and then will attack again. Uh, and misses with the second attack. That's a shame. All right.
Wade Brown: Yeah. That means he gets to hit back.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Number one kind of notices that you hit him, so he's like...
David Mendenhall: Surprised?
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, "You, you, you got..." He's like, it's kind of like... And he hit. Uh, does he hit?
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. And he swings his great ax.
David Mendenhall: And knocks me out again. Wow. God, I am not designed for tanking. No, no,
Kostadis Roussos: no, no, no
David Mendenhall: you- I know.
David Mendenhall: It's okay. I've le- Such senseless violence ... I think I'm learning my lesson on this one. All right. Soma, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, uh, you've learned a valuable lesson.
David Mendenhall: I, I am definitely learning things. I mean, why they wanted to fight me, I don't know. But they wanted to fight me. All right, I made my dice.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah. Uh, I don't know. We'll just, uh, thorn whip him again. He should die from that, right? Uh, actually, no, poison spray. That can do 1d12.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, what's the range of that?
Wade Brown: Uh, 30 feets.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So it's a target?
Wade Brown: It's... Yeah, it's targeted to-
Kostadis Roussos: Number one?
Wade Brown: Yeah. It's one
Kostadis Roussos: professional. It's number one dies.
Wade Brown: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Dies
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Um, orc number four. Hmm. All right, hold on. Let's get rid of... Let's get... Nobody, we aren't... You folks aren't doing their jobs getting rid of the orc, so we're down two and four. One, four. Okay. Re- I got, I got rid of it. I got rid of it. Okay. So- One, two, and
David Mendenhall: then as well. All right, I see.
Gary Young: Four, four is still up.
Gary Young: Three and four are up, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Well, a battle is not lost, they think to themselves. They can kill Valphine and it becomes two on two, so...
Gary Young: Yeah, that's not gonna help.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Wade Brown: Ignore the damage dealers.
Kostadis Roussos: Well- Uh,
Wade Brown: well,
Kostadis Roussos: that's not a hit. No, that's... Okay. Uh, Brub- Valphine, and you're up.
Gary Young: Uh, let's see. Uh-
Kostadis Roussos: Disengage is a good strategy.
Gary Young: Nah.
Kostadis Roussos: Nah. Yeah.
Gary Young: I'm enjoying the pain here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that's what I was worried you were gonna say. All right.
Gary Young: Uh, so let's see. They both are at full hit points. Okay, then I'll just attack four. Um- Mm-hmm ... and then we'll go with- Just a, a regular mace attack
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss Okay All right.
Gary Young: Br-
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry
Gary Young: Brewbarry will attack from here
Kostadis Roussos: Mm-hmm.
David Mendenhall: That's
Gary Young: cool, half of the
David Mendenhall: halberd. That is neat
Gary Young: He can just cleave again Mm-hmm
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit for seven points of damage on number three. All right, I marked it
Gary Young: And then cleave
Kostadis Roussos: That is how much damage? It's like six Six. Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on. When you're raging, you also add a certain number of points to your damage, which I don't think it add...
Kostadis Roussos: It does by default. True, yeah.
Gary Young: Yeah, but I forgot to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: You, again?
Gary Young: I mean, I guess I could rage right now 'cause it's my turn, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
David Mendenhall: Okay. Go ahead and do it, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right
Gary Young: Uh, and what is it-
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I, I almost feel that if Vukradin goes down, you automatically rage.
Gary Young: Not my long- Oh, right. Hold on
Gary Young: friend,
Wade Brown: long time
Gary Young: friend. Yes, yes. When Vukradin
Kostadis Roussos: goes down, I, I'll automatically rage. That's right. It... You're like... I, I think you automatically rage because, like, this is, you know, he's your... He's the mu- the musical genius of your life. All right, so you had... The first attack was nine points of damage, 'cause you get a plus- Yeah ... you get a, you get a plus two to fix that.
Kostadis Roussos: And the second attack is You do eight points of damage
Gary Young: All right. Rage bonus damage. What is my rage bonus damage again?
Kostadis Roussos: It's plus two. I looked it up last time. Oh. Uh, it's, uh, if you go to the, the second, the, the 2024 D&D rules under B- barbarian tables, it has a pl- it goes plus two. It's your proficiency bonus until a particular level, and then it goes to plus three, but it does not reach the same max as your proficiency, so it doesn't go to plus five.
Speaker 7: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All righty. Uh, orc number six. Okay, so orc three suddenly realizes... Hmm, is, is he clever enough to figure this out?
David Mendenhall: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he is. Um, so- He switches
David Mendenhall: targets?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, he, he doesn't advance. He throws his, uh, javelin.
David Mendenhall: Hmm.
Gary Young: At Brewbarry.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay. That's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Um. Yeah. He star- he hits and he starts c- and he says awful things about, uh, Earth guardian barbarians and, you know, questions their, the circumstances of their birth and, you know, all that sort of stuff.
Gary Young: I will shrug off five damage worth of it.
David Mendenhall: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: That is impressive.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Vukradin, death save.
David Mendenhall: That's a pretty sad combat for me. You're a bard. Failed. That was-
Kostadis Roussos: Failed. All right, Soma,
David Mendenhall: you're up. I like how you guys, like, stopped standing me up. That's, that's, that's appropriate. It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: It's almost
Wade Brown: done. Yeah, no, w- w- we'll
David Mendenhall: get you- Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah. We're going to, uh, we're probably gonna take down Valphine in the, in the fracas, but, uh, I don't know how much longer we got.
Wade Brown: So we're gonna ice knife the guy in the back, and it'll probably shard onto everyone.
David Mendenhall: Nice, do it
Wade Brown: Yeah. On target. Oh, nope, I just completely whiffed. Excellent.
David Mendenhall: No,
Kostadis Roussos: no, but does it, like,
David Mendenhall: just completely- There's still area damage though, right?
Wade Brown: Let me check, yeah. Uh, on hits, piercing... Hit or miss, the shard then explodes.
Wade Brown: Each creature within five feet must succeed dex saving throw or take 2D6.
Kostadis Roussos: Including Valphine.
David Mendenhall: Including Valphine. Including
Wade Brown: Valphine. I- I know.
Kostadis Roussos: At two hit points.
Wade Brown: I know.
David Mendenhall: Just make your dex save, you'll be fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, actually she won't. They, they, they'd already rolled the cold damage. It was seven.
Wade Brown: Oh, right, right.
Wade Brown: Two successes. Sorry. Um.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. I failed my dex save. So you are knocked out.
Wade Brown: Yes, but, uh, so is, let's see, Orc number one would be dead unless he makes his sa- actually, they'd both be dead unless they make their saves.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so what's the saving throw?
Wade Brown: Dex
Kostadis Roussos: 13. All right, D20, 2D20. Uh, one makes it, unless... Uh, both might make it.
David Mendenhall: They both- Uh,
Wade Brown: it's a 13, right?
David Mendenhall: I like that the- Grygum might make it ... the end result of your attack is that you killed your ally. And did no further damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, they all made it.
David Mendenhall: Well, no. That's-
Wade Brown: Well done.
Gary Young: So do
Gary Young: I do a death save now? If I do a death save right now? Yes.
David Mendenhall: Yes, you do. I'm sorry,
Gary Young: Valphine. Okay. Succeed.
David Mendenhall: Okay,
Gary Young: well you made it. The tactic, the tactical brilliance of this crew is, is,
Kostadis Roussos: is,
Kostadis Roussos: is- Look,
Kostadis Roussos: we're not
Wade Brown: a
David Mendenhall: well-oiled machine It'll get better. It'll get better ... we, we
Wade Brown: just met each other on the road,
Kostadis Roussos: right?
Kostadis Roussos: Like-
Kostadis Roussos: Well,
David Mendenhall: I- We took out the ogres quite effectively.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Uh, you take, uh, D6 plus three damage. You take five points of damage, Brewbarry, but that's halved because you're raging, so you're down to two points. You're down two points.
David Mendenhall: Down to 10.
Gary Young: Oh, I take half bec- I take...
Kostadis Roussos: Yes,
Gary Young: when
Kostadis Roussos: you're-
David Mendenhall: Half when you're down, right
Gary Young: oh, then I, then I probably took zero from the last attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay. Well...
Gary Young: All right, so you're saying I take two now?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay. All right.
David Mendenhall: Uh, Valphine, second death save
Kostadis Roussos: No, Vukradin didn't. It's, uh-
David Mendenhall: No. Well, nothing's up ... Valphine? Fail. Okay. Okay, you're at plus minus.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Brewbarry, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Can you please save the party?
Wade Brown: Yeah. Sorry, man. I'm still new to this whole magic thing
Gary Young: Brewbarry Are they fighting now? Yeah. Okay.
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry.
Gary Young: Well, we can, uh, just attack both of them with halberd again.
David Mendenhall: Yes. That sounds like a good plan. That's a hit.
Gary Young: All right. And that is-
David Mendenhall: And another hit Seven and that can be two kills. Dead. Yeah. They're both dead.
Gary Young: Hold on, hold
Kostadis Roussos: on, hold on. Let's make sure.
Gary Young: Seven
Wade Brown: and seven.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, right. Seven and ni- seven and n- no, it's nine and-
Wade Brown: Oh, 'cause you're forgetting your plus two. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You've got the-
David Mendenhall: They only have seven and six hit points, so
Wade Brown: That's
Gary Young: nine
Kostadis Roussos: and
Gary Young: nine, I think, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. It'd be nine and nine. Nine and nine. Yes. They are all dead. All right. I presume Brewbarry has to decide whether he's going to kill Soma, but maybe he doesn't.
David Mendenhall: I assume Brewbarry's gonna help Vukradin, his musician friend, right?
Kostadis Roussos: I, I think so. Yeah. Mm-hmm. And Soma, are you gonna help Valphine?
Wade Brown: I mean, absolutely I'm gonna help them up, kind of sheepishly.
Gary Young: So are we doing, like, medicine checks? Is that how this works again?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I, they're, I'm assuming since the combat is over, you're able to stabilize everybody.
Gary Young: Oh. Yeah. Okay. Sure, all right.
Kostadis Roussos: What? I, I'm, I... If it... Yes, right?
David Mendenhall: Um, long rest, everybody? Maybe we could go back in the bruin and lick our wounds and talk about what the hell had just happened.
Gary Young: Okay. Wait, hold on. Uh, yeah, go ahead and do that, and I'll search the bodies.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay. Yeah. I'll, uh, I'll head on over.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that sounds good. Yeah.
Wade Brown: Come on, Vukradin, let's, uh, let's get you back somewhere where you can perform.
Gary Young: Uh, okay.
Wade Brown: Tell tales of your brush with death.
David Mendenhall: All
Gary Young: right. He gets to enjoy the bodies. And the
David Mendenhall: orcs slaughtered us, slaughtered us. Yes, it was the orcs. And the orcs slaughtered us. Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so the orcs. So, okay. So then, okay. So, uh-
Gary Young: I
Kostadis Roussos: assume there's
Gary Young: nothing of value on the orcs. No,
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't say that.
Gary Young: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I just need to frigging find something. Um.
Wade Brown: They're suspiciously dextrous, so, you know, maybe they got something there
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm. There you go
Wade Brown: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: They've got a broken hadax, a javelin, and some hide armor
Wade Brown: Armor
David Mendenhall: Woo-hoo
Kostadis Roussos: Hide armor. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, you, you know, you could pick up the battle axes and try to sell them Four battle axes? Yep.
Wade Brown: Are they blood money battle axes?
David Mendenhall: Definitely. They're absolutely stolen.
Wade Brown: But you're not aware that this happened. You're just, you know-
David Mendenhall: As soon as I see them hit the party inventory, I will be.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry could cl- I mean, you know.
Wade Brown: Yeah, Brewbarry's just a walking arsenal, right?
David Mendenhall: From a practical standpoint, it's not money that's going to be shared with the Vukradin, so it's effectively the same as one
Kostadis Roussos: I see. So, Vukradin is, is optimizing for a poverty lifestyle.
David Mendenhall: No. Do you know how much these sending stones are worth? He's practically rich at this point.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know for a fact they weren't stolen?
David Mendenhall: I was given assurances that they weren't.
Kostadis Roussos: I'd say we've already become directionless. Plus I thought you were gonna
David Mendenhall: use the- I, I obtained those in a, in a fair, honorable way.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So, the, no, we're, we don't do provenance here.
David Mendenhall: There's only so much you can do, come on. Which wizard created them? How did he obtain the spell components for casting the, the sending spell?
Kostadis Roussos: And- I have a- Hold on, hold on,
David Mendenhall: hold on, hold on, hold on. How many asks? What?
David Mendenhall: Wade's not old. I don't think he can hear it I- Aw.
Kostadis Roussos: Exercise for people over city, 60. Begin by standing on a comfortable surface where you have plenty of room on each time. With a five-pound potato bag
Kostadis Roussos: in each hand, extend your arms straight out from your sides and hold them there as long as you can. Try to reach a full minute, then relax. Each day you'll find that you can hold this position for just a bit longer.
Kostadis Roussos: After a co- They say eating
Wade Brown: the potatoes.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, after a couple of weeks, move up to 10 potato, 10-pound potato bags. Then try a 50-pound potato bag, and eventually work your up, your way up to where you can lift a 100-pound potato bag in each hand and hold your st- arms straight out for more than a minute.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm at this level.
Kostadis Roussos: After you feel confident at this level, put a potato in each bag.
David Mendenhall: That was close.
Kostadis Roussos: resonated. Natasha said this resonated.
David Mendenhall: I heard.
Kostadis Roussos: Nice. Yeah. All
David Mendenhall: right.
David Mendenhall: Good night.
Kostadis Roussos: Good night. All right. Okay. So, uh, you, you show up here again, and, uh, Dazlyn and Norbus are like, "Oh, hi. You're back.
Kostadis Roussos: You're back" Are they...
David Mendenhall: They didn't die trying- They didn't- ... to steal the gem?
Wade Brown: They didn't have their, hear the fracas or anything? Like...
David Mendenhall: Are you sure they're not dead?
Kostadis Roussos: Did they do that? You told them where the
David Mendenhall: gem- They absolutely would've done that.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Um, no, I'm just trying to see when they did that. Like, you guys... I'm just thinking. Like, you guys went over there. Um, they wouldn't have done it the same day when you came out. They would've waked up in the morning. You guys went out to the orcs. The orcs attacked.
Kostadis Roussos: Mm-hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: So they probably kind of hid here to see whether you're alive or dead.
David Mendenhall: Mm-hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, because, you know, what's the point of having a gem if the orcs are gonna kill you? They're trying to decide whether they, they need to run, you know, whatever. They see you all come back. And, uh, Dazlyn and Norbus say, "Hmm, you're back."
David Mendenhall: Yeah, we're gonna camp for a while. We're really-
Kostadis Roussos: I see ...
David Mendenhall: a little beaten.
David Mendenhall: We're alive.
Kostadis Roussos: You're not here... They go, "You're not here for the gem, right?"
David Mendenhall: No.
Gary Young: We're here to partake of your hospitality. "
Kostadis Roussos: Ah. Ah." Dazlyn turns to Norbus, Norbus turns to Dazlyn. Um, "Well," uh, let's, uh, let's go over here and, uh, there's a nice little fire pit over here. And they s- they, they decide that it's an appropriate time to cook a, a pleasant meal.
David Mendenhall: Okay. That's
Kostadis Roussos: nice. All right. Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Kinda makes it all kinda worth it. Play my flute a little bit for them.
Kostadis Roussos: And it sounds like Vukradin made a, a new poem.
David Mendenhall: Yes. Oh. The orc slaughtered us, slaughtered us, slaughtered-
Kostadis Roussos: Um, well, you know. All right, so Vukradin, uh, they, they, they, the... So the next day, this is the third-
David Mendenhall: It was an average-
Kostadis Roussos: Performance,
David Mendenhall: yeah
David Mendenhall: performance. Uh, not my best Dazlyn
Kostadis Roussos: was unimpressed.
David Mendenhall: Mm.
Kostadis Roussos: Norquist was pleased.
Wade Brown: Keep at it.
David Mendenhall: I'll take at it. I'll take at it. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, yeah, they- A little bit But, but both of them were disappointed that you chose to play one of your own personal compositions instead of one of the more popular ditties of the area.
David Mendenhall: I'm sure they were.
Kostadis Roussos: Um-
David Mendenhall: I've heard that a lot.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: I've, I've gotten that a lot.
Kostadis Roussos: But, you know. All right. Are you guys gonna wait for them to go, or are you just gonna leave?
David Mendenhall: Oh, you mean we're... We long rested, and then I think we can head out.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, you're heading out. All right. Yay, you're heading out. All righty
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, where is this Sword Coast
Kostadis Roussos: All right, you're at the dwarven excavation
Gary Young: Back to Phandalin, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Back to F- back to Phandalin. Hold on, hold on.
Gary Young: I assume so. What, what's on our quest log?
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Gary Young: What's on our
Kostadis Roussos: quest log? Oh, yep. Well, uh, there, there's, or there's, uh, there were several quests
David Mendenhall: There was another... Oh, we have to get our 50 GP reward for this one Yes. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So let's first, let's go
David Mendenhall: get, let's go get the- Organic fair trade gold
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Yeah. What level are you guys?
David Mendenhall: One.
Wade Brown: One
Kostadis Roussos: On your way back
Kostadis Roussos: On your way back as you're heading towards, uh, Phandalin, you, um, s- hear a, you hear an ogre whistling whistling
David Mendenhall: What... I, I should be able to recognize the song
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, roll your performance I should be
Gary Young: able
Kostadis Roussos: to harmonize Roll your... All right, um
David Mendenhall: Uh, another 10. Not, not the best rolls.
Gary Young: I like- 23 perception. I assume I know where this ogre is?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Um, he is, he is, uh, coming up... Uh, you're, you're going on... It's, like, hilly terrain, so there's... If you could imagine sort of a hill like this, he's on that, that side, and he's coming up. So you guys can either try to meet him over there or try to sneak around
David Mendenhall: him. Valphine, may- maybe I should ask your opinion this time.
David Mendenhall: I- is this a fellow musician? He
Gary Young: seems like he would be a slave. I mean, that's normally what we would've did with ogres in Metzerbrod's time
Gary Young: At least he's one of these surface ones So
David Mendenhall: we free him then.
Gary Young: Free him? Yes, that's the way you do these things on the, on the, on the surface.
David Mendenhall: All right, let's free the slaves.
Gary Young: Uh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He did what? What?
David Mendenhall: Do,
Kostadis Roussos: do-
Kostadis Roussos: Slave, you
Gary Young: are
David Mendenhall: free. That is not the outcome I, I expected, but let's try to free
Kostadis Roussos: him. Slave, you are free.
Wade Brown: We don't even know if he's a slave. Who jumped to that conclusion?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Hold on. I now need to set up an encounter. Give me a second. Um- Oh, man. So
Kostadis Roussos: like, hey, here we go. All right. Uh, are there any, like, uh-
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So I do not have, I do not have... I will have to do it this way. All right. There is a, um,
Gary Young: Okay. Hold
Kostadis Roussos: on
Kostadis Roussos: Okay
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Right
Gary Young: Hmm. Good times.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay. So, and, um- Hmm
Kostadis Roussos: Mm-hmm.
Wade Brown: Okay. So, does he have any like bonds? Do we see any signs that he's actually a slave?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he's definitely not a slave. He's
Wade Brown: just a wandering ogre?
Gary Young: Yes. Get 11 insight on do I think he's a surface, uh, ogre.
David Mendenhall: Surface ogre?
Gary Young: Is he a surface ogre or an underground ogre?
Wade Brown: He's on the surface.
Gary Young: He could have been- I know ... you know, like when the demons invaded Menzoberranzan, you know, like there's all kinds of people from the under- underdark that, you know, made it to the surface.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, 11. Is there such thing as an underground ogre? Like ogres of the underdark?
Gary Young: There were plenty of them in the slave pits and in the, in the
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, to be quite honest, you...
Kostadis Roussos: To be quite honest, since there isn't actually a difference between them, you couldn't tell, you can't tell-
Gary Young: Okay ...
Kostadis Roussos: uh, with that level of insight. Okay. My higher
David Mendenhall: level of insight, you- I guess, I guess I would shout out at this point, "Ogre, are you a musician or a slave?"
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade Brown: I thought it would confuse anybody just whistling in the afternoon.
Gary Young: I hope you whistled the same song back to him.
David Mendenhall: I, well, I tried, but I only got a 10 on my performance, so it wasn't so good
Kostadis Roussos: Uh,
Gary Young: okay. Apparently ogres
Kostadis Roussos: covet food and treasure, and they spitefully destroy art
Wade Brown: But he was whistling. That's making art.
David Mendenhall: Oh, slave?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. He... You called him a musician. He, he's like, "
Kostadis Roussos: Me? Musician? Music? No. Me kill you. How dare you?"
David Mendenhall: Wait, he doesn't like music? Oh, I'm definitely rolling for initiative
Kostadis Roussos: then.
David Mendenhall: 21.
Gary Young: All
David Mendenhall: righty. That's what you get for hating on music.
Wade Brown: Ugh. Oh, this kid's gonna get us all killed
Gary Young: Think
David Mendenhall: of all the blood money you'll get from killing him
Wade Brown: I don't need blood money
David Mendenhall: All right Nice roll,
Wade Brown: Valphine
David Mendenhall: Yeah You did. She did.
Gary Young: All right.
David Mendenhall: I know, we, we did very well on that one.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: All right. Well, I will, uh, definitely attack. All right. Valphine, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Mm-hmm. All right, hold on Um, the white surface is all, uh-
Wade Brown: Grassland or whatever?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, grassland ...
Wade Brown: plain or something like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep. I- Easy terrain.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, easy terrain. That's the important thing. Moving, uh, moving between levels costs you... It makes it extra-
David Mendenhall: Hmm. I don't plan on moving, so good to know.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Like, if you were to... Going down costs you double movement, going up costs you double movement, and it's 10 feet. That's where the- So reason- Okay.
Gary Young: So I assume that- Uh, your,
Wade Brown: your
Kostadis Roussos: guide said for five
Wade Brown: feet ...
Kostadis Roussos: the battle is joint. Yes, yes. The, the battle is joint. Yeah
Gary Young: Uh, dex save 13 All righty.
David Mendenhall: Are we gonna do 59 damage? This is gonna be a pro- this is gonna be a process.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, he takes four points of damage.
David Mendenhall: Four
Gary Young: damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Well
Kostadis Roussos: done. Does Valphine stay within 30 feet, which is his movement rate, or does she s- take a few steps back to try to avoid being within his charge range?
Gary Young: Uh, Brewbarry's gonna be in front.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. That's Valphine's new strategy. All right. Brucriddian, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Uh, Starry Wisp.
Kostadis Roussos: What does that do?
David Mendenhall: What's the to hit on this ogre? 11, perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: That's a hit
Kostadis Roussos: What does that do?
Wade Brown: Damage.
David Mendenhall: Eight radiant.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Uh, so eight points of damage.
David Mendenhall: And the range is 60 feet, so I can definitely head back over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Uh, who is next? Brewbarry.
Gary Young: Rawr,
David Mendenhall: charge. Rage?
Kostadis Roussos: Don't
Gary Young: forget to
Kostadis Roussos: rage.
Kostadis Roussos: Remember, he said he doesn't like music.
Gary Young: Yeah, that's right.
David Mendenhall: Mm. Unbelievable.
Kostadis Roussos: I know.
Kostadis Roussos: Um- Okay, roll to hit.
Gary Young: Of course, I can't cleave, but- No
Gary Young: Is that a bonus? Oh, no, no. Plus, plus two attack with the-
Kostadis Roussos: Is it ... I don't, I only think it's for damage, though.
Gary Young: Is it only damage?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Gary Young: I don't know. I'm-
Kostadis Roussos: They changed everything.
Gary Young: They- It's hard for me to know how my abilities work. Um-
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I'm not expecting you. I'm kind of like, like this is like sort of like, I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: I'd like ... I have to go read the new player's handbook. Hold on.
Gary Young: Yeah, gee, yeah. Damage resistance, rage damage
Kostadis Roussos: It's dash damage, it's not to hit
Gary Young: Advantage on strength checks Sorry,
David Mendenhall: guys. Ignore that.
Gary Young: Yeah. Okay, just advantage on strength checks. So a 10 is a miss, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: All right then. But I'm now reading.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. All right. All righty. Ogre. Well, the ogre marches up to you and says- Oh, you left a square with my ... Uh, yeah, it is true.
Kostadis Roussos: All right A crit Wow. Um
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Plus four points of damage
David Mendenhall: You ranged though, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. So that's 19 plus four, because you doubled the, um... Okay. He's down to 24. Damn.
David Mendenhall: Nice. Halfway
Wade Brown: there.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Well, yeah, he's, he's kind of like, "Damn."
David Mendenhall: That was, that was impressive. All right, the ogre is up.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, well done.
Kostadis Roussos: All right
Kostadis Roussos: That's 10 points of damage, or five points of damage if you're raging
Gary Young: Uh, guess I'll take the five points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Good call.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay, uh, Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: All right. We'll come on up a little closer and just cantrip away. Let's go poison spray. Uh, that's a hit, right? He's 11? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, yep, that's a hit.
Wade Brown: Seven damage, taking him to 17.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. There's no poison condition related to poison spray, right?
Wade Brown: No, it's kinda weird. It just does 12, 1d12 poison damage. That's it.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. And Balthany? 1d12
David Mendenhall: is pretty nice.
Wade Brown: Yeah, it's a really nice cantrip.
David Mendenhall: Wow. It just does nothing. I don't have anything that does 1d12.
David Mendenhall: That's awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Dex- Dido ...
David Mendenhall: dex save DC
Gary Young: 13.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Ogres have really bad dexterity, so that is a good choice
Gary Young: That's all I kind of options
David Mendenhall: Oh
Gary Young: That's a crit on-
David Mendenhall: He got a natural 20. All
Gary Young: right
David Mendenhall: Uh, what's he down to? 17.
Gary Young: 17 will not be
David Mendenhall: the end of my turn. Or could he-
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming she stepped over here and then stepped over here. Wilkrideen, you're up
David Mendenhall: Hit.
Kostadis Roussos: What did you just hit with? Starry Wisp? Yeah With Strangler? Okay
David Mendenhall: Three, three Radiant. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You did that. All right. Only three?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, well, it's not a great damage roll. All righty
Kostadis Roussos: Is that another miss? Yeah. That's another miss. You literally had a 25% chance to miss. It's not that
Wade Brown: rare.
David Mendenhall: Did, um, did somebody record the three damage?
Kostadis Roussos: No, could you please do that? Oh,
Wade Brown: yeah. He's at 14
David Mendenhall: now. There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, Brewbarry is done.
David Mendenhall: Ogre
Kostadis Roussos: is up. All right. Yes, the ogre is up
Kostadis Roussos: Ogre does nine points. Uh, what is Voo- Very's armor class? No, misses.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wow. Okay.
David Mendenhall: Mm-hmm. All right, Soma.
Wade Brown: All right, hypothetically, I could Thorn Whip him away from you. Would you get an opportunity atta- Yeah ... attack of opportunity?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you would.
Wade Brown: All right, let's do that. I'm gonna come over here and just try to yank him away so you can get a free hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade Brown: Yeah, it looks like, uh, that's pretty good.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so what does that do? Oh, you missed again.
Wade Brown: Uh, 'cause he takes 1D6, uh, and I pull him 10 feet closer, so I do have to pull him out of the way, so move him, like, just move him one square over.
Kostadis Roussos: 5, 10. Right, that's five feet, that's 10 feet. All right. He's right next to you, and he's also knocked prone, right?
Wade Brown: Uh, it doesn't say anything about prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, fine. Then he's only n- all right, fine. He's-
Wade Brown: Yeah, I was just trying to get me a attack. Oh, well.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: How about- Uh, we did record that's six damage, so there's another... He's at eight
Gary Young: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: L.T., you're up. Okay. Do not die with this team. Sacred Flame might work this time.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Again, a good choice.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, this time it does work, and he takes five points of damage. Uh, did someone apply it? No, I, no. No,
Wade Brown: he should be at three now.
Kostadis Roussos: He's at a three. All right. Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: Uh, I just... No,
David Mendenhall: Voo- No,
Wade Brown: it's,
David Mendenhall: uh, it's Vukradin ...
Wade Brown: Very v- yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: There it is. I
Wade Brown: was at the bottom.
David Mendenhall: Gotta move my token a little bit, and then-
Kostadis Roussos: No wait, hold on. Brewbarry just went, right?
Wade Brown: No.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Valphine.
Wade Brown: Valphine just went.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Soma just went. Yeah, sorry, I got confused. Yeah, I
David Mendenhall: did,
Wade Brown: I did the Thorn Whip.
David Mendenhall: Lemonade?
Wade Brown: Brewbarry missed his attack opportunity. Valphine did Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, got it. I just got- I got-
Wade Brown: That's death if he dies. Dead. Or if he takes the whole damage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, he dies.
David Mendenhall: He's dead.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Die, you anti-musician slave
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let's see what does treasure does he have?
Wade Brown: I had no idea you were so easily triggered.
David Mendenhall: I had to fight orcs, had to fight an ogre, ochre jellies. This is not what I signed up for.
Gary Young: What? What did you sign up for?
David Mendenhall: Well, we were just supposed to go tell the dwarves that there was a dragon in the area and then go back to town
Kostadis Roussos: All right. You find a walloping am- ammunition on him A
Wade Brown: what?
David Mendenhall: No doubt stolen from another adventurer
Kostadis Roussos: A creature hit by this ammunition must succeed in a DC saving throw or have the prone condition
Gary Young: Who has range weapons?
David Mendenhall: Not it.
Gary Young: Not
Kostadis Roussos: me All right, well
David Mendenhall: You can always sell it, guys.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry. All right. Okay. Um, you find the walloping ammunition in a... Um, fortunately for you, the, the, the ogre did not know how to use it Oh, that's
David Mendenhall: fortunate
Kostadis Roussos: Um, possibly because the ogre prefers just walloping people
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. You know, the ogre is, uh, modus vivendi. All right, so you arrive in Phandalin.
Gary Young: So is there a reason that Valphine does not have a hand crossbow? I mean, she is a drow.
Kostadis Roussos: No, she can have a hand crossbow.
David Mendenhall: You can buy one.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I almost feel like, uh, uh, uh, a drow without a hand crossbow is, is kind of like not a real drow.
Gary Young: Yeah, seriously.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. It's sort of like less of a drow. Um, all right. You arrive in the Townmaster's Hall.
David Mendenhall: It is time to collect our reward.
Kostadis Roussos: Mm-hmm.
Wade Brown: Our justly earned gold pieces.
David Mendenhall: Honorably earned. All
Kostadis Roussos: right
Kostadis Roussos: All right. You show up at the, uh... Let me just see this one more
Kostadis Roussos: All right. See what happens. I need to do something
Kostadis Roussos: All right Okay. So we arrive at the Townmaster's Hall. Um, uh, to your... Uh, you knock on the door and the door is again closed shut. Do you knock on the door? Yeah. All right.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I want my money.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Uh, da, da, da, da, dump. Uh, right. He goes, "If, if you're..." You hear a voice again going, "If you're a dragon, know that I'm far too thin and Boney to make a good meal."
Wade Brown: Dragons aren't usually the type to knock.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh- Sometimes. What?
Wade Brown: Sometimes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. You do remember that asking him about a quest, um, a b- uh, talking to him about a quest gets him to walk out of his room So you're asking about the q- so last time you, you asked him about a quest. He, uh, he stopped, like he, he's not responding to you.
Kostadis Roussos: "Th- you could be a trick. I don't know it for a fact that you're not the dragon, so just go away. I'm too skinny."
David Mendenhall: I'm sure I can get this out
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: I got a 20 persuasion. I should be able to persuade him out the door
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, uh, he, this, "Oh, oh, I, I think I've heard your voice before. You're, you're that bard that played in the Stonehill Inn."
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that's me. You
Kostadis Roussos: remember me? "Yes, yes." All right. "
David Mendenhall: I, I,
Kostadis Roussos: I, I, I know we, we, um, no?" "But, but, but I do recall...
Kostadis Roussos: No. Sorry. Should I remember you?" That's
David Mendenhall: a point. Well, anyway, we came here for our money. "
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you came here for your money.
David Mendenhall: Uh, so did you get-" Yeah, we told the dwarves about the dragon "
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you, you told... Oh, excellent, excellent, excellent. I, I'm feeling very much happy. They were, they're very charming people, you know?"
David Mendenhall: Eh, they seemed kind of like grave robbers
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: You don't think?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, uh, uh, he pauses and goes, "What do you mean do they think they're grave robbers?"
David Mendenhall: Well, I mean, they were, you know, digging in a ruin for artifacts, and I, I don't think they were intended to put all those artifacts in a museum
Kostadis Roussos: Hubbard goes, "Uh,
Kostadis Roussos: The, his Lor- his Lordship, Neverember / Lord Neverember, said that adventurers are allowed to seize and control whatever treasure they wish
David Mendenhall: Well, that doesn't seem right at all
Kostadis Roussos: Uh-
David Mendenhall: Anyway, I will go with my typical diatribe
Kostadis Roussos: Harbin has this look. If, if you, do you wanna roll your insight? Does anybody wanna check their insight or investigation? All right,
David Mendenhall: insight.
Kostadis Roussos: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Alfie picks up that he is very unhappy With? With,
Gary Young: um, Vukradin- With Vukradin's behavior
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Vukradin's, uh, morality? Yes. Uh- Well, did
David Mendenhall: he pay me my
David Mendenhall: 50 gold pieces?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he did.
David Mendenhall: All right. Well, that's all I really care about.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. But, but the, the, the, the, the, the... He is very upset with, uh, what he's heard
Gary Young: You're upset with the orcs attacking the
David Mendenhall: dwarves? You're upset with, with a fine, upstanding, moral citizen of Faerûn?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes. He's, he's... Well, I mean, do you, do you ask him about it?
David Mendenhall: No, I'm just surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Well, I'm just telling you, I'm d- uh, I'm just saying he seems very upset, anxious even.
David Mendenhall: Interesting. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. All right, so, um, you... There are the next set of quests. Um, Harbin says, "Well, um, since you seem to be in the business of, uh, uh, being a, a hero, I don't want to take any more treasure.
Kostadis Roussos: The good news is that I have plenty more quests for you."
Gary Young: Awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, excellent. We, we seem to be having a shortage of adventurers these days, something about the dragon terrorizing everyone.
Gary Young: How about something other than dragon?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, I suppose I could get you something other than dragon. We do, we always have, uh, uh, we...
Kostadis Roussos: He, he turns to the, the, the, the... You won't have any real issue with the, um-
Kostadis Roussos: All right, he goes, all right. Okay, what's, uh... Okay, so there's, okay, there's two more quests. Let me see whether I can have, let me see. They, they actually provided this
David Mendenhall: Rock gnomes and the midwife?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Yes. Oh, they don't have the, uh, quest as, uh, as
David Mendenhall: that thing. That's fine. We have it copied nicely into the spreadsheet.
David Mendenhall: Which one paid better? I think it was the gnomes paid better, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: All right. I vote gnomes.
Wade Brown: I'd rather the starving
Gary Young: artist
Kostadis Roussos: And I think we stop at the shop Need more organic fair trade gold All right. Okay. Um- We
Gary Young: stop at the shop and sell our blood money. Or-
Kostadis Roussos: Um, uh, to the line shield coster?
Gary Young: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: What about the sending stones? Should we keep those or sell them off?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, you're not gonna have anybody to sell them off in this town.
David Mendenhall: Oh, interesting. Okay. Well, I guess we're keeping them then.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Um, in terms of the weapons, you can sell them to the smithy. Um, he'll be happy. He'll be happy for half price.
Gary Young: For half price. Uh,
Kostadis Roussos: they'll be damaged. That's what you get. They're damaged
Gary Young: Uh, half price, not 90% price?
Kostadis Roussos: No, half price. They're damaged.
Gary Young: Okay. So all right,
Kostadis Roussos: half price. They were damaged. Sorry, yes. Um- I don't know if... I, if I didn't say that, that's my, uh, my bad.
Wade Brown: Feel like you did.
Kostadis Roussos: I think I did.
Gary Young: Okay. It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Um-
Gary Young: And same with the hide armor
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, the hide armor is in fine shape. You can sell that to Lionshield Coster for scale- for what is, uh, not l- the thing that's just one step above the leather armor, leather armor.
Gary Young: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Mail
Gary Young: armor? It's normally worth 10 gold, so ...
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so you can sell it for 10 gold.
Gary Young: For nine, I assume, 'cause we have
Kostadis Roussos: our- Well, y- yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yep
David Mendenhall: And the jeweled dagger and the gemstones.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, who do ... Let me ... Who do you sell, who do you sell those to? Barthen's Provisions? Um- Tell us. Let me just see. Hold on.
Gary Young: The jeweled dagger might go to the blacksmith. He might find that interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, hold on. I'm trying to see something. Where is Phandalin? Sure. Yeah, there we go. That's what I was looking for
Kostadis Roussos: Right
Wade Brown: I'll be back in a moment
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay. All right. Okay, so fine. All right, so you, you go to the... So while you're going, uh, to the various stores, to the smithy, to Lionshield Coster, um, when you get to the Lionshield Coster store, um, uh
Kostadis Roussos: Lininni, uh, she t- she tells, she says, "Oh, you're still alive."
Gary Young: This time.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Excellent. Excellent. Um I had
David Mendenhall: several near death experiences. It's a new thing for me. I've never had this happen before.
Gary Young: The pain was glorious.
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at, she looks at you awkward and she goes, "Well, as you know, ever since, uh, the, uh, s- ever since, uh, the, um, Lionshield Coster had...
Kostadis Roussos: It used to have a, a big business. Uh, unfortunately there were things that happened that have made our business, uh, not as able to, uh, provide all the goods that people would like, but we're still in business.
Gary Young: What has disrupted your trade?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, you know, th- that's sort of an in busi- th- th- uh, supply chains, sup- s- the, the-
David Mendenhall: Tariffs
Kostadis Roussos: so it's all very technical. Tariffs. What?
Gary Young: Tariffs.
David Mendenhall: Tariffs.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, yes, tariffs. Tariffs, that's the word. Reciprocal
Gary Young: tariffs. Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Uh, t- tariffs, um, some disruptions, uh, market force dynamics.
Gary Young: Mm-hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Uh-
David Mendenhall: Do you need any help with that?
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at you and says, "Well,
David Mendenhall: uh..." Like, do you, you have a shipment that you need us to go procure for you, or,
Kostadis Roussos: or- Oh,
David Mendenhall: maybe that
David Mendenhall: we transport it poorly, or, you know, can we offer our services?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh. It
David Mendenhall: would be a fair and honorable way for us to earn money.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh. Oh, that's what you meant. I thought you meant to actually solve my problem of the... Oh, ah. Oh. Uh, yes, but not today. I'm not expecting a shipment. Um-
David Mendenhall: But was there another problem you needed help with?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, no, no, actually, the... Not really, but I did hear a rumor.
Gary Young: What's the rumor?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, strange magic pervades Neverwinter Wood, confounding navigators and obscuring the ancient ruins of bygone kingdoms lost in its depths. Here, I'll cut and paste it.
Kostadis Roussos: Whoa.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I put it, I cut and paste it into the, uh, the, the, the, the chat I put it
Gary Young: in the bus tracker.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. And so, um, she says, um, "Will you be staying at the Stonehill, Stonehill Inn?"
Gary Young: Yeah, I suppose so. I mean, what,
Kostadis Roussos: what
Gary Young: time is it? Is it- I
David Mendenhall: guess we do have the money for that now. That's amazing. Treat yourself.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, yeah, you know, it's like the Stonehill Inn is, uh, is gonna be open for business
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Brew time. All right, you arrive at the Stonehill Inn, and Toblen, the, uh, Stonehill Inn tavern keeper is, is Toblen Stonehill, is very happy to see you, and he says, "Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit. It's so wonderful to see you."
Kostadis Roussos: Um-
Gary Young: Yes, wonderful to see you, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, hold on one second. Beer? Uh, what? Did you say beer?
Gary Young: Wonderful to see you, too. Beer?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, "Excellent, yes, beer." Hold on. Da, da, da, da, da, da, da,
Gary Young: da. Beer, song.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, he goes, "Well, I can't do song, but I, if I recall correctly, your friend here does an excellent, uh, song." Ah. Do
David Mendenhall: you have a piano?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I still haven't bought a piano.
David Mendenhall: So flute or clarinet then?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, are you asking if I have any of those instruments?
David Mendenhall: No, no, no, I have one. W- which would you prefer? I'm happy to play.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, f- f- flute or clarinet, well, whichever one you prefer. I, uh, clarinet.
David Mendenhall: That's a good choice.
Kostadis Roussos: Cla- clarinet.
David Mendenhall: Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Clarinet.
David Mendenhall: I assume you want one of your pop numbers.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I, if I recall correctly, you, you, you, you were doing some, something that you did that was very, very good.
David Mendenhall: Okay. I get it's an aver- an average performance.
Kostadis Roussos: Good music, good music. What is
Kostadis Roussos: with
Wade Brown: your plus five never
David Mendenhall: hitting above, like, 20? Yeah, I don't know, I don't know.
David Mendenhall: I've been rolling badly tonight.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, all right, okay.
David Mendenhall: Where's my 25 performance? I want that.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Um, so he goes, "Okay, that won't work." Um, so, all right, so there's a few more people in the town, in the, the inn. Um, you can ask if they have any more, um, if they've heard any more rumors, or you can go spend the night, uh, sleeping.
David Mendenhall: Go ahead, guys. I'm just playing the flute.
Gary Young: Uh, I guess Valphine will check the mood of the crowd.
Gary Young: Uh- All
David Mendenhall: right ... '
Gary Young: cause, you know, everyone loves a drow asking questions. Nothing
Wade Brown: sus about
David Mendenhall: that. Totally normal, completely fair. Yeah, it'll be fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, yeah. So, so what, so roll your perception or investigation. Roll your insight or investigation.
Gary Young: All right. Insight.
David Mendenhall: Eh. Now you're plus fiving an average.
Gary Young: Jeez. So with all my attack rolls, uh, with plus five, and then this one with plus five.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Um, quite honestly, you know, you can't really tell.
David Mendenhall: Thoma, you wanna take a, take a, take a try? Oh, sure. A uber... How about Brewbarry?
Gary Young: No, he's busy listening to the music.
David Mendenhall: I mean, I have a minus one. Of course he is. Sure. There you go. Oh, yeah. Lovely. Love... Jesus Christ, guys.
Gary Young: Okay. Uh, so we just have our existing quests.
Gary Young: Uh, I guess that's fine.
David Mendenhall: All right. So are, are, are- There's always the next trip to
Kostadis Roussos: the inn ... are, you, so you're not gonna ask anybody?
David Mendenhall: No, we did.
Gary Young: We did.
David Mendenhall: All
Kostadis Roussos: right. I,
David Mendenhall: I got him a five.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I thought he was, like, doing an investigation to see if anybody, what every, the moo-
Gary Young: He was. He was You should see it rolls
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, good grief.
Kostadis Roussos: I, did I miss something really funny?
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry. I was trying to come up with rumors and frantically going through my DMG guide.
Gary Young: No, you don't need to bother with that.
David Mendenhall: We didn't roll well enough
Kostadis Roussos: for that. Don't worry. All right. Uh, okay. All right. Um, okay, so the next morning and off to Gnomengarde, right?
David Mendenhall: And that cost us a gold.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm. It didn't actually say that. Um-
David Mendenhall: I assume the town's not, the inn's not free, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I just, I just realized that.
David Mendenhall: One gold. That's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: One gold. Yeah, let's just make it one gold.
David Mendenhall: That's fair.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So, um, off to Gnomengarde.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, where is this? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, I didn't put you on
Kostadis Roussos: the right map. All right, here we go. Gnomengarde. So you go through... Do you wanna go through the hilly terrain, go through the grasslands, or just head... Like, how do you wanna go?
Wade Brown: Which direction is it? Oh, sorry. Oh, it's the dwarven activation. No, wait, that's
Kostadis Roussos: where we came
Gary Young: from. Oh, no.
Gary Young: Hold on. Sorry, sorry. I just realized.
David Mendenhall: Where is it?
Gary Young: Valphine would like to go through the most brightly
Kostadis Roussos: lit, uh, path possible. At both
David Mendenhall: paths. Oh, just, just go straight.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Through the hilly terrain.
Gary Young: Through
Kostadis Roussos: the, um...
Gary Young: Right?
David Mendenhall: How well
Gary Young: does that- This path has key tree cover. I need to have this sun.
David Mendenhall: 10 miles.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, no, it's, it's 15, it's 15 miles.
Gary Young: I always thought you were allergic to the sun.
David Mendenhall: Make that and we'll-
Gary Young: No, no. The sun is gloriously painful.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you're, you're not really understanding, like, like, the whole, uh, Valphine, Valphine thing. Um- Okay. Let's see
David Mendenhall: what we have here. What do we have to do with the gnomes? Let me, let me look. Remind me. How, how quickly
David Mendenhall: can we get
David Mendenhall: this done? Uh. It says- Gnomes are known for their magical inventions. They might have something to do with the key to the dragon. Get whatever you can from them. So just, we just need to trade with the gnomes. Okay. That's, that's fast. We can trade very quickly. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: And hold on. Hold on, hold on, hold
Wade Brown: on.
Wade Brown: Holding on, holding on,
David Mendenhall: holding on. We can get whatever we can. We might be able to get nothing, and then we've gotten whatever we can, and we get our 50 gold pieces.
Wade Brown: Technically correct. The best kind of correct.
Speaker 7: Hold on. Give me one second
Speaker 7: Oh, so it's a few this way. Okay
Speaker 7: Vacuous truth
Kostadis Roussos: As you're going through, uh, um
Kostadis Roussos: So imagine this is a, you're, you're going through the mountains, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Mm-hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, as you turn around the corner, um, so imagine this is a mountain pass kind of thing. A ogre is standing in the middle of the way.
David Mendenhall: Another ogre.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Althena, is this one a slave too?
Kostadis Roussos: Let me check.
Wade Brown: Is it whistling?
Gary Young: 14.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it's defin- no, not a slave '
Gary Young: Cause usually when they're slaves, they, they don't whistle cheerfully.
David Mendenhall: So he just wants to kill us then, like the other one.
Gary Young: Uh,
David Mendenhall: the- Seems like everybody out here just wants to kill us.
Kostadis Roussos: Because the ogre goes Um. I hungry. I eat you. Oh, we have
David Mendenhall: food. We have food.
David Mendenhall: Can we just give you some food and you, you can stand over there? 'Cause we're just walking past you. Can we do that?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at, he, he looks... I like turtle.
Wade Brown: Excuse me.
David Mendenhall: I don't have any turtle. I'm not on the menu. I have some rations.
Kostadis Roussos: Hm. Turtle. I eat turtle.
Wade Brown: No, no eat turtle. We don't.
Kostadis Roussos: Do we have something else to feed him?
David Mendenhall: Anybody?
Kostadis Roussos: Um, you can tr... Y- so the, he's, you're gonna have to try, if you want to persuade him, you're gonna have to either in- you're gonna have to intimidate him.
Wade Brown: Intimidate
David Mendenhall: an ogre? Okay, I guess I could try that. I just- That's not
Wade Brown: happening ...
David Mendenhall: it's not usually my style, but let's see what happens. Nope, nope,
Kostadis Roussos: nope.
Kostadis Roussos: You, you do not succeed in intimidating
David Mendenhall: him. You guys wanna try intimidation? I- Go for
Kostadis Roussos: it ... kinda
Wade Brown: do.
David Mendenhall: Ugh. All right. Max. Is that the
Kostadis Roussos: great new- Try it,
David Mendenhall: try it ...
Kostadis Roussos: plan? Yeah, I mean-
David Mendenhall: Oh, yeah, Valphine, you gotta roll. See if you can get him to
Kostadis Roussos: run. Do I?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, you gotta try. Excellent. Well done, guys. Well done.
Wade Brown: I told you, you don't intimidate ogres.
Kostadis Roussos: It's just- And just,
Kostadis Roussos: just for the record, uh, I don't think the
David Mendenhall: ogre- Those are pathetic rolls, guys ...
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no. I don't think the ogre was intimidated.
David Mendenhall: We know. We know.
Kostadis Roussos: In fact, I think the ogre now is excited because he saw your attempted intimidation and thinks this is gonna be an easy... He goes, "Uh, eternal elf..."
David Mendenhall: I've killed other ogres like you. Yeah.
Wade Brown: And- Just yesterday we took out one of your brothers ...
Kostadis Roussos: wait, did you say that?
Wade Brown: Uh-
David Mendenhall: Yeah, we should get a plus two. Yeah, I would say that. I'm getting kind of ticked off now- Yeah, let, let Bl- ... that he wants to kill
Wade Brown: me ... yeah, let Vukradin say
David Mendenhall: it. All I ever wanted to do was play music,
Kostadis Roussos: but-
David Mendenhall: jeez. Why? "
Kostadis Roussos: You killed my brother and sister." I think it actually-
David Mendenhall: You still have not- ... suggests you did ... enraged him further. I love it.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a free rage. Yeah. All right. It enrages him.
Wade Brown: Uh- Nice going, kiddo. You just ticked him off ...
Kostadis Roussos: all right. Okay, let me just put an ogre in the combat tracker.
Wade Brown: Ugh, another one.
Kostadis Roussos: I...
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, it's, it, you know, it's like what you encounter on the, uh- Combat in
David Mendenhall: this module.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Wade Brown: No,
David Mendenhall: it's fine. It's fine ... no combat in the module.
Wade Brown: Eh.
David Mendenhall: All right. Well- I'm gonna have to stop, I think. Let's-
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Should we stop at the end of this?
David Mendenhall: I'm gonna try some different spells. Got some other ideas
Kostadis Roussos: Right
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, Valphine and Brewbarry, you need to put your, uh, um, initiative rolls Uh, 11
Gary Young: and nine
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, okay. Right. All right, Soma, you're up
Wade Brown: Oh man, I'm first. How did that
Kostadis Roussos: happen? Yeah.
Wade Brown: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So just to give you an idea, right, you're in the middle of a sort of a valley with a-
Wade Brown: Yeah, no, I was wondering if I could just like mold earth and rocks on top of him or something.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, uh- I love it ... uh.
Wade Brown: I mean, he's literally surrounded by,
Kostadis Roussos: you know, earth.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I'm just trying to... Yeah, I'm, I'm actually saying yes, but I just don't know how to measure the damage.
Wade Brown: Yeah. It's, uh... Does this actually have a roll? What happens when I roll? Oh, it just does that.
Gary Young: You can just roll cantrip damage if you wanna make it
Kostadis Roussos: easy.
Wade Brown: Well, you know, I like the idea of
David Mendenhall: making- I mean, it would be, it would be like the dirt that's above him, you would loosen it and then it would fall on him.
Wade Brown: Yeah, you just get
David Mendenhall: like- Especially from quite high up
Wade Brown: Could make a good rock slide or something onto him, you know? Like
Wade Brown: We make a big old, basically like a rock avalanche come down on him or something. Right.
David Mendenhall: It says this movement doesn't have enough force to cause damage.
Wade Brown: Well, yeah, but from up above, it's taking all that poten- That big fall, the big fall damage ... that potential energy gets converted into damage. Like dropping a penny off the Empire State Building.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah, yeah.
David Mendenhall: Can that kill you?
Wade Brown: I don't think it can, but that's just because pennies have a very low terminal velocity.
David Mendenhall: And math.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: And very little
Kostadis Roussos: damage. All right, all right, all right. So I will declare that it would cause, uh, 1d6 worth of damage.
Wade Brown: All right, we'll just poison spray him.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Screw being creative.
Wade Brown: Well- Good old poison spray. Nothing beats that ... it was a good
Kostadis Roussos: idea.
Kostadis Roussos: No, yeah, unfortunately the mold earth spell, the problem with it- Oh, it's
Wade Brown: fine. It's not meant for damage. I just kind of wanted to screw around. Hey. Um, so I'll just do, uh, what
Kostadis Roussos: is that? But, but, but you could tr- yes, um, you could have used it to, uh, make the terrain difficult so he can't charge at you.
Wade Brown: Yeah, but that also makes it hard for Brewbarry to get in there.
David Mendenhall: I have better ideas than that. All right. All right, eight damage.
Wade Brown: Yeah, 51. And I'm actually gonna scoot back since he said turtle was sort of his favorite food.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Oh, yeah. Um, fortunately he made, he made a saving
David Mendenhall: throw. P- put me in front.
David Mendenhall: Thanks, dude.
Wade Brown: You're the one who pissed him off.
Kostadis Roussos: This
Wade Brown: is, uh- Um, poison spray doesn't have a saving throw ...
Kostadis Roussos: oh, it's a hit. Oh, it's a hit, right. Sorry, my bad.
Wade Brown: Yeah, he just takes eight damage, like-
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes ... no
Wade Brown: question. Yep.
David Mendenhall: All right, ogre's up.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Ogre's like
Kostadis Roussos: All righty
David Mendenhall: I taste bad. Don't come after me. Um. No
Kostadis Roussos: No, hold on.
Gary Young: Our, our turn order leaves something to be desired.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, our, our marching order was not, uh- Our
Kostadis Roussos: marching order I, I don't think that would be... He would be here.
David Mendenhall: I, I think, I think I would be in the back. Okay. I'm gonna be in the back.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Actually, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think...
David Mendenhall: That looks more sane.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. I, I can't imagine that would've been your order.
Gary Young: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh-
Gary Young: He exited a square that I'm threatening.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh-huh.
Gary Young: Uh.
David Mendenhall: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. That's four points. All
David Mendenhall: right, ogre, ogre is up first.
Gary Young: Um- Yeah, but I still get my reaction on him, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. You take four points of damage. He takes
Gary Young: four.
Gary Young: Yeah. I'll, I'll get it.
Wade Brown: Forget to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: He doesn't get to rage up until... It, uh, uh, he gets to rage on his turn, not- Yeah, it's okay ... his reaction. All right. So the ogre
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, swings his axe, uh, and rolls a one
David Mendenhall: Oh, that's a miss Cuts off his
Kostadis Roussos: own toe Valphine
Gary Young: Valphine Valphine. He can ... Oh. Hmm. I, I guess they would have a high strength save, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes
Gary Young: Uh, I, I can walk on this, uh, dark gray?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Uh, just every time you go on it, it's c- counts as 10 feet of movement. Uh- Okay ... going, going up on it costs you 10, and so you can then move normally on it
Gary Young: So I move twen- 20, I guess?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep
Gary Young: Okay. Uh, and I'll just use my mace
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, no, you can't. Then you have to go back down, so you'd have to go through Brewbarry He missed
David Mendenhall: anyway. He missed anyway
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just saying you might wanna use your spell. That's what I'm trying to say
Gary Young: Okay. I will use my spell instead
Kostadis Roussos: Or a ranged wea- or a ranged weapon.
Kostadis Roussos: That, that, that's what your choices are
Gary Young: Well, maybe I should try this new ha- hand crossbow
Kostadis Roussos: All right, try the new hand crossbow. Gosh darn it, that is a hit. Are you using one of the special bullets or you're just using it for damage?
Gary Young: Sure. Roll a strength save DC 10?
David Mendenhall: You should be able to make that
Kostadis Roussos: I don't
David Mendenhall: What's your plus on strength saves?
Kostadis Roussos: Four
David Mendenhall: Oh, wait Still Oh, okay. All right. He's prone then?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's prone. Okay.
David Mendenhall: And he takes three damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep Okay.
Gary Young: Yep.
David Mendenhall: Did you get the damage?
Gary Young: Uh, I'll get
David Mendenhall: it. Uh.
David Mendenhall: Okay. Agree All right, got him
Gary Young: You got it
David Mendenhall: Use a Baldur's Gate 3 standby
Kostadis Roussos: What was that?
David Mendenhall: Make a DC 3, DC 13 wisdom save. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Blows it. Okay. Man.
David Mendenhall: He is halted and can take no actions until the end of his next turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, well, well.
David Mendenhall: Nor can he move.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Brewbarry.
David Mendenhall: Well then.
Gary Young: All right, so he is, uh, prone, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep. And halted. So that is 12 points of damage.
Gary Young: Uh, with, with, uh-
Kostadis Roussos: 14
Gary Young: points
Gary Young: plus two rage, so 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'll get, I got that.
Gary Young: You got that.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All righty
Wade Brown: Yeah, back to the top of the order is me.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Or, okay, let's, uh, just do you, Soma, and we'll stop after that 'cause it's 10:30.
Wade Brown: Uh, yeah. Um, yeah. I think I'm still best off just doing poison spray, right? Just hit it. Hit it and get out.
Wade Brown: There.
Wade Brown: All
Gary Young: right. Oh, boy,
Wade Brown: another four damage. Well... Right.
Gary Young: Okay. And we will stop here. Uh, should we just do the ogre's turn, which is to be skipped?
David Mendenhall: Yep, to, to do nothing, and then- All right. Yeah, yeah ... and then remove the halt condition.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep. He's still prone.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, but Valphine, Valphine starts next week.
David Mendenhall: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, excellent. Okay. Oh, next week, oh, next week we will not be playing 'cause I will be in Greece, probably hopelessly inebriated at this time, recovering from my inebriation.
David Mendenhall: Well, at this time in Greece, it'll be 7:30 in the morning. You're gonna be drunk at 7:30 in the morning?
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, so, or recovering.
Wade Brown: Hair of the dog.
David Mendenhall: You're not sure which one or the other.
Kostadis Roussos: Just a logical or here. Yes.
Wade Brown: There will be alcohol. There'll be blood in your alcohol system.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Um, so I, I don't think I'll be able to be awake. Um- All right ... all right, guys. Take care.
David Mendenhall: Bye-bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Bye. Bye.